// Republic Day was first celebrated at Rajpath :in the year 1955.
// Constitution of India are handwritten which were signed by 308 Assembly members on January 24, 1950.
// For how many days  is Republic Day celebrated :for 3 days
// President Sukarno, Indonesia’s first President attended Republic Day celebrations as the first Chief Guest.
// Time taken to draft the Indian Constitution : 2 years and 11 months to draft 
// The concept of Five Year Plans in the Indian Constitution has been borrowed from the Constitution of the USSR and not the UK.
// Before the Constitution came into force, India followed British Government’s Government of India Act 1935.
// "Satyamev Jayate," which was one of the biggest Indian motto is taken from the Mundaka Upanishad, Atharva Veda.  
// The national song ‘Vande Mataram’  was indeed part of his novel Anandamath 
// Dr Rajendra Prasad took oath  as India’s first president
 

var questions=[
    {
      "question":"When was Republic Day first celebrated at Rajpath?",
      "option1":"1950",
      "option2":"1951",
      "option3":"1956",
      "option4":"1955",
      "answer":"4"
    },

    {
        "question":"How many Assembly members signed The Constitution of India ?",
        "option1":"545",
        "option2":"308",
        "option3":"256",
        "option4":"350",
        "answer":"2"
    },

    {
        "question":"How many days does the Republic Day celebration continue for?",
        "option1":"7 Days",
        "option2":"2 Days",
        "option3":"3 Days",
        "option4":"1 Days",
        "answer":"3"
    },
    {
        "question":"Who was the Chief Guest of India's First Republic Day?",
        "option1":"President Sukarno",
        "option2":"Tribhuwan Bir Bikram Shah",
        "option3":"Queen Elizabeth II",
        "option4":"Rab Butler",
        "answer":"1"
    },

    {
        "question":"What was the time taken to draft the Indian Constitution?",
        "option1":"2 years and 5 months",
        "option2":"2 years and 8 months",
        "option3":"2 years and 9 months ",
        "option4":"2 years and 11 months",
        "answer":"4"
    },

    {
        "question":"The concept of Five Year Plans in the Indian Constitution has been borrowed from which country?",
        "option1":"Germany",
        "option2":"UK",
        "option3":"USSR",
        "option4":"USA",
        "answer":"3"
    },

    {
        "question":"Before the Constitution came into force,which Act of British Government was followed by India?",
        "option1":"Indian Contract Act, 1872",
        "option2":"Government of India Act 1935.",
        "option3":"Indian Councils Act, 1892",
        "option4":"Government of India Act, 1912",
        "answer":"2"
    },
   
    {
        "question":"Moto Satyamev Jayate, is taken from which of the following Vedas?",
        "option1":"Atharva Veda",
        "option2":"Rigveda",
        "option3":"Samaveda",
        "option4":"Yujurveda",
        "answer":"1"
    },
    {
            "question":"Who took oath as India’s first president?",
            "option1":"Dr Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan",
            "option2":"Dr Rajendra Prasad",
            "option3":"Dr Zakir Hussain",
            "option4":"Varahagiri Venkatagiri",
            "answer":"2"
    },
    
    {
        "question":" The national song ‘Vande Mataram’ was indeed part of which novel?",
        "option1":"DurgeshNandini",
        "option2":"Anandamath",
        "option3":"Kapalkunda",
        "option4":"Mrinalini",
        "answer":"2"
    } 

];